JOSHUA SHANE EAGLE

Full Stack Developer HTML5/CSS3/JavaScript/Responsive & Adaptive Design/Mobile-First/MV*/Asynchronous Coding/JAVA/Node

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Specializing in Web Development, I have worked in the industry with a vast background of different technologies from the Back-End, Front-End, and DEVOPS. All of these experiences have enabled me to understand what needs to be done not only for my work specifically, but for those who work in tandem together to achieve common goals. Additionally, my experience has empowered me to create powerful applications that adheres to the high standards of the industry, as well as cross-compatibility with multiple devices including mobile, all the way up to desktop.

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer (Full-Stack)

Praxis Engineering, Chantilly, Virginia

Designing, architecting the Next Generation of android apps for the State Department, using android tablets that have finger print scanning, MRZ Code reading, and using NFC scanning.

Devices:

Android Tablets

Stack:

Front End: NativeScript Vue

Back End: Java

Testing: Appium, Jest, Junit, SonarQube

DevOps: Jenkins

Web Application Developer (Full-Stack)

Unisys Corporation, Fairfax, Virginia

Designing, architecting the Next Generation of web applications for the United States Customs Border Protection. Where I have received high marks for out-of-box thinking improving the design and ease-of-use for each application.

Devices:

Desktop Browsers: Chrome, Safari, Firefox, IE11+

Stack:

Front End: Node, @angular/cli (Webpack, jasmine, and other tools included in the cli)

Back End: Java with Spring Boot, Junit

Tool Set

@Angular/cli

@Angular/Material

Bootstrap

CSS3

Docker

HTML5

Jasmine Unit Testing

JavaScript

JSON

Karma

Lodash

NativeScript

Node.js

Python

React

Restful Services

Ruby

Rxis

Selenium (web driver)

SonarQube

TypeScript

Vue.js

March 2020 - Present

September 2016 – March 2020

Webpack

Web Server Experience

Apache/Tomcat

Express

IIS

Nginx

Database Experience

MongoDB MySQL

Design Experience

Photoshop Illustrator

OS Experience

Linux Mac

Windows

Active Security Clearance:

Public Trust

Certifications

AWS - Certified

Testing: Ruby, Selenium Web Driver, testing Back End API and Front End UI, SonarQube *DevOps*: Jenkins, Bamboo, OpenShift with Docker

Awards:

Gold Global Recognition, Silver Global Recognition (Both for Outstanding Performance), BEST UI Design of the USBP Hackathon 2017

Principal Consultant (Front-End Developer)August 2013 – September 2016 **Longview International Technology Solutions Inc.**, Fairfax, Virginia

Responsibilities include working in an agile environment, creating responsive, mobile-first web applications using Backbone/Marionette and Angular, executing 508-compliance, and phone-gap. My entire stay with Longview I worked on the Veteran Affairs Project.

- Maintained applications like Scheduling Manager, Veteran Appointment Requests as well as many other applications Front-End as well as the Back-End. Fixing bugs, running Fortify Scans, and deploying the applications to Nexus preparing them for deployment. I have also worked on a DevOps team of three individuals in order to implement a Docker environment breaking new ground in a frontier that is in its infancy for the VA.
- Applications Developed: 8 (Telederm, Stroke-Pathway, Scheduling Manager, Veteran Appointment Request, Warfarin, Secure Messaging, Vitals, Labs, and Radiology). For Telederm, I worked with a Back-End developer to create the front-end bits of the application. For Stroke-Pathway, I implemented the Cordova components so that the application could run under Android as well as iOS. The rest of the applications I worked with a team of 6, (2 Front-End, 3 Back-End, and 1 tester), I worked as a Front-End developer using the technologies listed below in the Stack section.

Received high marks for Scheduling Manager as well as Veteran Appointment Request, which also received recognition from the 58th Speaker of the United States House of Representatives, Newt Gingrich.

Devices: All smart phones / tablets.

Desktop Browsers: Chrome, Safari, Firefox latest 4 versions, IE9/10+ (depending on app)

Stack:

Node, Angular, Backbone/Marionette, Handlebars, Underscore, Require, Modernizr, JQM, Twitter Bootstrap, Grunt.

Consultant (UX Developer)

April 2012 - August 2013

CGI Federal, Fairfax, Virginia

Responsibilities include working in an, agile environment, creating responsive web pages for government entities such as the Federally-Facilitated Exchange, and Centers for Medicare & Medicaid Services. My most recent work on the Federally-Facilitated Exchange has been presented at the White House for the new health care law that was passed under President Barack Hussein Obama.

Freelancer

October 2011 – April 2012

Navigant Consulting, Inc., Washington D.C.

Responsibilities include the development of bash scripting in the Linux environment, managing trouble tickets, and bug reports for the scripts. Trouble-shooting code, implements bug fixes, and maintaining the overall structure of the Linux environments for Navigant.

Associate (Developer)

June 2010 – February 2012

DRT Strategies Inc., Arlington, Virginia

Responsibilities include the development of Google Custom Search features, development with Drupal front and back-end, standing up and maintaining server infrastructure, creating mockups for websites using Photoshop, slicing those mockups into HTML5/CSS3 themes which are cross-browser compatible, 508 compliant, and w3c validated. Maintaining database infrastructure and supporting the IT infrastructure within DRT Strategies.

EDUCATION

B.S., Information Technology George Mason University

January 2007 - May 2010

Minor: Business Dean's List